Dilan Patel

201 Kingshill Drive, HA3 8QT • +44 7963145174 • dilantpatel@hotmail.com

PROFILE

I am a goal driven, responsible 3rd year Computer Science student looking to enhance my skills through a summer placement program. During my education I have been able to successfully combine my work with personal interests, proving myself to be organized and independent. My logical approach to problems ensures that every task I do is completed to the highest standard and on time.

EDUCATION

University College London, MEng Computer Science (Expected 2020); Predicted 2.1

Key Modules:

Object-Oriented Programming: 73%

Engineering Challenges: 71% Systems Engineering: 73%

Queen Elizabeth's School Barnet (2009-2016)

A Level: Mathematics (A*), Physics (A), Geography (A), Chemistry (B)

AS Level: Further Mathematics (B), Critical Thinking (C)

EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS

Microsoft Cities Unlocked, London

Systems Engineering Module (2nd year university)

Assisted in development of an iOS augmented reality game for visually impaired players in collaboration with Microsoft. Was involved throughout the whole development cycle, including user requirement formation, prototyping, and development of a final solution.

- Developed an iOS application front-end.
- Responsible for documenting progress through creation of bi-weekly reports to present to Microsoft.
- Extensive research into solution space and effective app creation.

UCL Engineering Tutors, UCL

Physics and Mathematics Tutor (2017-Present)

Currently work as a mathematics and physics tutor supporting GCSE students prepare for exams. Work involved planning tailored, 1-on-1, sessions for students to enhance their understanding of varied subject areas and ensure their understanding of core ideas. Gave insights into STEM subjects at higher education levels.

- Improved my student's grade from a C to an A.
- Clarified various aspects of engineering at university to students.

International Transport Workers Federation, London

Service Desk Analyst (Intern) (Summer 2014)

Worked as a part of the IT team to prepare for upcoming digital conferences. Gained experience of how Computer Science is applied in a commercial situation as part of a larger organization.

- Responsible for testing and resolving laptop builds.
- Deployed tablets for training purposes and assisted with training documentation.
- Data research and cleansing of CRM data.

KEY SKILLS

Programming Languages: Through my course, I have become proficient in a number of languages including C, Java, and Swift.

Software development: I am familiar with all stages of the development life-cycle, including user requirements analysis, testing and deployment.

Communication: Writing reports as part of university projects, as well as working with younger people, has made me effective at communicating complex ideas both verbally and visually.

Teamwork: Being a member of a student society committee and collaborating on university projects has helped me to understand how to work effectively and efficiently within a team.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

UCL Gaming Society, Students' Union UCL

Committee member (2017-Present)

A significant contributor to expanding a relatively new society to its current state of over 150 members. Worked closely with large organizations to run socials, LAN events, and large-scale tournaments.

- Help to ensure weekly tournaments are run as scheduled.
- Manage various teams within the society and compete on a national level.
- Organized social events including Varsity series against other London universities

Dominos Pizza, London

Customer Service Representative (2014-2016)

A front of house team member responsible for taking customer orders and handling queries or complaints in a polite manner. Responsibilities included managing cash transactions and maintaining store cleanliness. Also assisted with training new employees

- Adapt to the needs of the team in a dynamic working environment.
- Ensured orders were processed and delivered efficiently and correctly.
- Worked to maintain a professional image of the company through exemplary customer service.